ycharts.com 2019-12-27

# Privacy Policy - YCharts

**YCharts, Inc. (“YCharts”, “we” or “us”) is committed to protecting your privacy.**

Your privacy is our priority. In this privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) we explain our practices regarding the information that we collect through our website ycharts.com (the “Site”) from users, including you, how that information may be used, and with whom it may be shared. Capitalized terms not defined in this Privacy Policy have the meanings given in our Terms of Use located at https://ycharts.com/about/terms. This Privacy Policy may be modified in the future. When we post changes to this Privacy Policy, we will revise the ‘last updated’ date at the bottom of this Privacy Policy. We recommend that you check our Site from time to time to inform yourself of any changes in this Privacy Policy. YCharts is not responsible for the content or the privacy policies of any web sites to which it may link.

**User Consent**

By visiting our Site, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy and you expressly consent to the collection, use and disclosure of Personal Information (as defined below) in accordance with this Privacy Policy. The term “Personal Information” is used throughout this Privacy Policy to describe information that can be associated with a specific person and can be used to identify that person. We do not consider Personal Information to include information that has been anonymized so that it does not identify a specific person.

**Geography** **:**

YCharts is a U.S.-based company that offers its Services to domestic and international business customers. As a result, information that we collect, including Personal Information, may be transferred to our U.S. offices to permit us to comply with our legal and contractual obligations, to provide information and services to prospective and current clients, and to perform related business activities. In addition, we may provide information to third-party service providers in the U.S. and in other countries to the extent necessary to support our business activities, and we may access Personal Information collected by our customers to support the Services that we provide to our customers. Thus, Personal Information may be transferred to and stored on servers located in the United States and in countries different from the country in which that information was initially collected. Similarly, information we collect may be accessed by YCharts and our third-party service providers and business partners from countries other than the ones in which the information is stored.

If you have any questions or concerns about this Privacy Statement or about our privacy or data security practices, please contact us at dataprotection@ycharts.com.

**What information do we collect?**

In general, when you visit the Site we may collect your IP address and standard web log information, such as the pages you accessed on our Site. We may also collect certain geo-location information. If you do not agree to our collection of this information, you may not be able to use our services. When you register and open an account to use one of our services, we may collect the following information from you:

**—** Identification information such as your name, e-mail address, telephone number, and home address.

**—** Financial information such as your payment method if you transact business with us (valid credit card number, type, expiration date or other financial information).

**—** Limited account information and transactions such as your investing account assets and transaction history for YCharts Portfolio’s Subscribers, and information related to your contact with our customer support team.

**—** We record certain information and store it in log files when you interact with our Services. This information may include Internet protocol (IP) or other device addresses or ID numbers as well as browser type, Internet service provider, URLs of referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, information that you search for, your locale and language preferences, your mobile carrier, and system configuration information. We and our analytics providers, also collect and store analytics information when you use our Services to help us improve our Services.

**—** We may require additional information from you before permitting you to use our services to verify your identity or to manage risk and compliance throughout our relationship. We may also obtain information about you from third parties such as identity verification, fraud prevention and similar services.

**Why do we collect the information we collect?**

We collect Personal Information and anonymized information to provide You with the Service, to perform marketing campaigns, research related activities, to supply other administrative services (e.g., setting up new accounts and maintaining your existing account), to respond to inquiries about your account and the Service and to support our legitimate interests to conduct business with You. In addition, we may from time to time review your usage of the Service to be able to better provide you with information about products or services that we believe may be interest to you and to inform our efforts to improve the product to your specific needs.

You may request that We stop tracking or collecting your Personal Information by emailing [dataprotection@ycharts.com](mailto:dataprotection@ycharts.com).  In such cases your ability to utilize the product will cease and your account information will erased, as long as local rules and regulations allow YCharts to do so.

**How do we use the information we collect?**

In general, Personal Information you submit to us regarding you or your company is used to deliver our products and services, manage your account and to provide you with the services and customer support you request. We may use financial information such as your payment method to process payment, to protect against or identify possible fraudulent transactions, and as otherwise needed to manage our business. In addition, Personal Information or anonymous log file information may be used to perform statistical analyses of user behavior in order to measure interest in the various areas of our Site, for development purposes, and to inform advertisers and partners about users clicking on their advertising or other messages.

Using the e-mail addresses provided by users who register for an account with us, YCharts, its advertisers, affiliates, partners, or third parties may periodically send promotional e-mail. In any case where we might use an e-mail address for this purpose, you will be able to indicate during the registration process that you do not wish to receive such promotional e-mails from YCharts, its advertisers, affiliates, partners or third parties. However, by registering for an account with YCharts, you agree that YCharts may contact you by e-mail regarding account status, changes to applicable terms and conditions that may apply to you, and to confirm registration. In addition, if you provide your e-mail address or other contact data in connection with a request for product information, YCharts, an advertiser, affiliate, partner or third parties, as applicable, will use that information to contact you.

**With whom do we share the information we collect?**

YCharts may share your Personal Information with third parties for direct marketing purposes, but only if you have authorized YCharts to do so. We may share your Personal Information with third party service providers as necessary to: provide you with the services that we offer you through our Site; conduct quality assurance testing; facilitate creation of accounts; process any payments; provide technical support; and/or provide other services. Additionally, if you entered the Site through a web site maintained by one of our affiliates or business partners, then your Personal Information may be shared with that affiliate or business partner, provided that use of the Personal Information does not violate this Privacy Policy. This Site contains links to other web sites. While we encourage our business partners to adopt privacy policies that build users’ trust and confidence in the Internet, we are not responsible for, do not review, and have no control over these outside websites, their privacy practices or their content. We may also disclose your information, including Personal Information, when we believe disclosure is appropriate in connection with efforts to investigate, prevent, or take other action regarding illegal activity, suspected fraud or other wrongdoing; to comply with applicable law or cooperate with law enforcement; or to enforce our Terms of Use or other agreements and policies.

**How to update your Personal Information?**

If you should want to update information collected during registration for a YCharts account, you may update that information by: 1) logging into your YCharts account and clicking “manage account” or 2) email [dataprotection@ycharts.com](mailto:dataprotection@ycharts.com) to request specific edits or information about the Personal Information collected.

You are responsible for the accuracy of Your Personal Information and it is recommended that you periodically check to ensure that yours is accurate.  Additionally, should you wish to delete your Personal Information, please email [dataprotection@ycharts.com](mailto:dataprotection@ycharts.com) to make the request.  YCharts will reply as soon as possible but no longer than 30 days.

**What should I know about “Cookies”?**

We use various technologies to collect information, including cookies that we save to your computer or mobile device. Cookies are small data files stored on your hard drive or in device memory. We use cookies to improve and customize our Services and your experience; to allow you to access and use the Services without re-entering your username or password; and to count visits and understand which areas and features of the Services are most popular. We may also associate the information we store in cookies with Personal Information you submit while on our Services. You can instruct your browser, by changing its options, to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from websites you visit. If you do not accept cookies, however, you may not be able to use all aspects of our Services.

**How we protect Personal Information**

Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet or data storage system can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. That said, we certainly try very hard, employing a variety of organizational, technical and administrative measures to provide a level of security appropriate to the risk associated with the Personal Information you trust us with.

**Data Retention**

We retain your Personal Information only as long as necessary to accomplish the business purpose for which it was collected or to comply with our legal and contractual obligations, and then securely dispose of that information.

**Information for International Users**

Our Services are hosted in the United States. You may choose to use our Services in non-U.S. regions, such as the European Union or other regions of the world with laws governing data collection and use that may differ from U.S. law. Please note that when you use our Services, you are transferring your information outside of those regions to the United States for storage and processing. By providing your information, you consent to any transfer and processing in accordance with this Policy.

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us (support@ycharts.com).  If you have specific questions or requests related to Your Personal Information, Your ability to request to view your Personal Information or Your ability to delete Your Personal information please reach out directly to our Data Protection Officer via dataprotection@ycharts.com.

**Last Updated August 30, 2019.**
